KHANH KING

Atlanta, GA, 30350 | khanhnphan15@gmail.com | Linkedln | GitHub | Portfolio

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I'm a dedicated software engineer with 2+ years of experience working on complex full-stack products based on client specifications. My journey began with a year of self-study and an internship at Meldcore, transitioning into my first contract Software Engineering role. This experience honed my skills in a professional setting. After completing an immersive coding boot camp, and learning web development in JavaScript, Python, and React, I'm excited to join a dynamic team and apply my skills while enhancing my technical proficiency.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Ember JS, MongoDB, JSON, Node JS. **Libraries and Frameworks:** React, Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Bulma.

AWS Cloud technologies: S3, Lambda, EC2, RDS.

Databases and other: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful Routing, JSON API

Interpersonal skills: Self-learning, teamwork, and time management.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Meldcore LLC, Software Engineer, Contract

Atlanta, GA, 07/2021 - Present

- Managed Heart Zones fitness app's front-end and back-end with a collaborative engineering team.
- Created a responsive front end using Ember JS, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS, while employing Python for the back end and Post SQL for the database.
- Self-studied Ember JS, Python, and JavaScript during training. Gained insights from senior engineers about product intricacies.
- Implemented a RESTful API for centralized data and business logic.
- Manage cloud deployment utilizing AWS EC2, RDS and S3.

Willmer Engineering Inc, Accounting Assistant

Atlanta, GA, 06/2018 - 12/2020

• Provided administrative support to the controller, managed the day-to-day tracking of expenditures and profits, processed expense reports in Deltek Vision, and reconciled accounts payable transactions.

H&R Block, Accounting Assistant

Atlanta, GA, 01/2017 - 06/2018

• Evaluated financial records, including income statements and expenditure documentation, to identify necessary forms for tax return preparation and audits. Skillfully completed and submitted income tax, sale tax, and payroll returns for both companies and individuals.

Quynh Nhi CPA, Bookkeeper

Atlanta, GA, 03/2016 - 12/2016

• Assisted accountants and tax preparation, contributing to month-end closure, reviewing balances, journal entry posting, creating reports via Accounting Software, and performing periodic reconciliations.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Nota Nobile - GitHub | App - Python | Django | AWS S3 | PostgreSQL | Materialize CSS | Boostrap CSS

- A Django-powered web app showcases fine Italian dining, blending custom CSS and Materialize CSS for a stylish, dark-themed look.
- It directs users dynamically through reservations and meal views, while securely storing data in a PostgreSQL database. The intuitive admin panel aids staff in managing dishes and wine pairings, ensuring a streamlined experience for both users and staff.

Musix Box - GitHub | App - MERN | React | Javascript | Node JS | Express JS | MongoDB | React Semantic Ui

• A web app allows users to share, stream, and curate audio files. With JWT for authentication, users have a personalized homepage to manage uploads and playlists. The platform supports mp3 file uploads for seamless audio experiences.

- Streamline HR is an application for managing employee data, showcasing profiles with details like name, email, DOB, and position.
- It's built on Javascript and CSS Flexbox, enhanced by Bootstrap for UI, and uses MongoDB and Node.js for backend operations. The app ensures precise formatting and incorporates Google authentication for secure logins.

Hangman Game - GitHub | App - HTML | CSS | JavaScript

Generate a random word, guess the word using single words as input, and display the length of the word.

- Wrote game logic in JavaScript and styled with CSS Flexbox layouts and CSS transform property which modifies the coordinate space of the visual formatting model.
- Applied affine linear transformations to HTML elements.

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Full-stack Engineer

Georgia State University, Bachelor of Science in Accounting

Atlanta, GA, Graduated: 05/2018

University of Alabama at Birmingham, Bachelor of Health Science Management Birmingham, AL, Graduated: 05/2011